Running tumbling is going to be a great way for the whole entire squad to show off their tumbling skills.
Now granted, every squad is going to have tumblers of different levels.
A lot of squads are going to have people who can just do the round-off back handspring; all the way up to people who can master double fulls.
Now when you're doing your running tumbling, usually you want to make sure you can get as much distance as you can, as much run, and it's all going to start off with the round-off back handspring.
That's where we're going to get all of our momentum from.
Now if the round-off back handspring is the highest skill you've mastered, that's wonderful, and you're going to go ahead and be the first person to go on your squad.
Usually what we try to do is build the tumbling from the lowest level all the way up to the highest level.
Now the most common tumbling pattern that we're going to use on cheerleading squads is what we like to call the X.
We're going to have a group of tumblers in line, facing diagonal on the left hand side.
We're going to have a second group of tumblers facing diagonal on the right hand side.
Then you're going to designate which side is going to go first.
They're going to do their running, their round-off back handspring, all the way till you land.
And then you need to continue stepping off your floor.
Now it's really important for these to go really fast for them to be effective.
So as soon as you see the person cross in front of you, you want to start with your run.
And it's going to be really great because we're going to have a lot of building momentum.
We're going to have someone go with the handspring, someone go with the handspring tuck, someone go with the handspring full, someone go with the double layout full.